linccweb.org 2006-12-28

# LINCCWeb - Privacy Statement

> > Information CCLA Uses  
>  Personal Information  
>  Cookies  
>  Security  
>  Links to Other Web Sites  
>  Applicable Laws and Policies  
>  Contact  
>  Changes to this Privacy Statement   
>  The College Center for Library Automation (CCLA) provides LINCC (Library Information Network for Community Colleges) and affiliated Web sites: LINCCWeb ( _www.linccweb.org_) and the CCLA Web site ( _www.ccla.lib.fl.us_). LINCC supports local library operations at Florida's 28 public community colleges.
>> 
>> CCLA is committed to protecting the privacy of registered users of LINCC services and visitors to our Web sites. CCLA does not collect personally identifiable information about users of LINCC services or visitors to our Web sites except as needed to provide services you request, services to which you are entitled by your affiliation with a Florida public community college, or if you choose to disclose that information to us. We do not share information about individual users with any third party except as needed to provide services you request or for authorized law enforcement activities. CCLA staff use registration and statistical information to improve services and tailor them to suit your needs, to provide easier access to advanced features, and to help us serve you better.  
>    
>  **Information CCLA Uses**
>> 
>> CCLA collects usage information for statistical purposes and to support local library operations. For Web site management, CCLA software programs create summary statistics that are used for such purposes as assessing interest in site content, determining technical design specifications, and identifying system performance or problem areas. CCLA collects and stores the following information: 
>> 
>>   * Internet domain (for example, " _xyzcompany.com_ " if you use a private Internet account, or " _yourschool.edu_ " if you connect from an educational institution's domain) and IP address from which you access our Web sites 
>>   * Type of browser and operating system used to access our Web sites 
>>   * Date and time you access our Web site 
>>   * Pages you visit on our Web sites 
>>   * Internet address of the Web site from which you linked directly to our Web sites 
>> 
To support local library operations, CCLA collects and temporarily stores information required for LINCC system use, including your eligibility status as a registered borrower and the LINCC-based services (such as borrowing library-owned materials) you have requested. Such information is made available to the community college library with which you are affiliated and may be acted upon by employees of CCLA or that library in the course of delivering the services you have requested. Your use of LINCC to obtain local library services is also subject to the privacy policies and practices of the institution from which you have requested services.Back to Top
>> 
>> **Personal Information**
>> 
>> CCLA considers any information that could reasonably be used to identify you individually as personally identifiable information. This includes, but is not limited to: your name, address, email address, phone number, Social Security number, and institution-assigned ID number. CCLA takes reasonable steps to assure data integrity and to protect personally identifiable information from unauthorized disclosure. CCLA uses only personally identifiable information supplied to us by you, your institution or local library, and updates all data regularly. Personal and usage-related information is deleted when it is no longer needed to manage services delivered via LINCC or LINCCWeb. Personally identifiable information, including the SSN (if used), is collected and maintained by your local institution. Any changes to this information (other than to your PIN) must be made through your local institution.
>> 
>> You will need a Borrower ID number to borrow library materials or to login to LINCCWeb services. For secure access to LINCCWeb services, you will also need to enter a Personal Identification Number (PIN). The ID number is made up of 9, 14, or 16 digits, as determined by the institution with which you are affiliated. A 9-digit number may be based on your Social Security Number (SSN). Your PIN is initially assigned when your Borrower ID is added to the LINCC system and usually consists of the last 4 digits of your SSN. Since PINs may vary by institution, please check with your local library. You should change your PIN immediately when you use it for the first time. CCLA automatically receives personally identifiable information from your local institution to create and update your Borrower ID number, or an employee of that institution enters the information directly into the LINCC system.
>> 
>> Some personal information is accessible to you on LINCCWeb through a secure login to services such as My Account. Personally identifiable information, library materials currently checked out or requested, and fines owed, may be displayed on the screen during your session. Although some online sessions are set to time out automatically after a period of inactivity, you should always close the browser window promptly after any session in which personally identifiable information was entered or displayed. Closing the browser window will prevent another person from viewing your personal information. For more information on how you can protect your personal information on LINCCWeb, please see our [FAQ](http://www.linccweb.org/FAQs/linccweb.asp#question_13).
>> 
>> If you submit personally identifiable information when requesting information or services from CCLA (as in an e-mail message or an electronic form) we will use this information to respond to your request. Your e-mail may be forwarded within CCLA for our staff to assist you. We may also forward requests for assistance to another appropriate institution (such as your local community college) for response. Other than the foregoing reasons, we do not share e-mail or other personally identifiable information with outside organizations without obtaining your permission.
>> 
>> Back to Top
>> 
>> **Cookies**
>> 
>> "Cookies" are small bits of information generated by a Web server that are either used for the duration of a session, or saved on a user's computer in order to identify that user (or information about that user) the next time they log on to a Web site. We use cookies to facilitate delivery of several LINCCWeb applications. For example, we use a cookie in conjunction with LINCCWeb's "Electronic Resources" Web page so that you do not need to enter your borrower ID more than once during the same browser session. This cookie is deleted when your session ends and is not collected or saved. 
>> 
>> Back to Top
>> 
>> **Security**
>> 
>> The security of the information that you provide is very important to us. We utilize industry standard encryption for all transmissions. The encryption technology helps ensure the private, secure transmission of any personally identifiable information.
>> 
>> Only authorized CCLA or library staff with assigned password may access personally identifiable information maintained in LINCC or LINCCWeb and then only for the purpose of performing work related to the delivery of services as described here.
>> 
>> Back to Top
>> 
>> **Links to Other Web Sites**
>> 
>> Transactions within the CCLA/LINCC network are transmitted within a protected environment. Once you link from CCLA's Web sites to another site, you are subject to the privacy policy and security practices of the new site. Such linking does not constitute CCLA's endorsement of the new site's privacy policy. Please refer to CCLA's Terms of Use Statement for more information about links from CCLA's Web sites to other Web sites.
>> 
>> Back to Top
>> 
>> **Applicable Laws and Policies**
>> 
>> Privacy and public records obligations are governed by applicable [Florida statutes](http://www.leg.state.fl.us/Statutes/index.cfm) and [U.S. laws](http://uscode.house.gov/usc.htm). CCLA is committed to protect the privacy and integrity of personally identifiable, non-public information of students in compliance with the [ Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA)](http://uscode.house.gov/uscode-cgi/fastweb.exe?getdoc+uscview+t17t20+3710+0++%28%29%20%20AND%20%28USC%20w%2F10%20%281232g%29%29%3ACITE%20%20%20%20%20%20%20%20%20) and the [Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (GLB)](http://uscode.house.gov/uscode-cgi/fastweb.exe?getdoc+uscview+t13t16+2769+4++%28%29%20%20AND%20%28USC%20w%2F10%20%286801%29%29%3ACITE%20%20%20%20%20%20%20%20%20). Confidentiality of library registration and circulation records is protected under [ Section 257.261, Florida Statutes](http://www.leg.state.fl.us/statutes/index.cfm?App_mode=Display_Index&Title_Request=XVIII#TitleXVIII). CCLA's use of personal information is also subject to the policies of the Florida Community College System.
>> 
>> Back to Top
>> 
>> **Contact**
>> 
>> Please contact CCLA if you have questions about this Privacy Statement.
>> 
>> Only authorized CCLA or library staff with assigned password may access personally identifiable information maintained in LINCC or LINCCWeb and then only for the purpose of performing work related to the delivery of services as described here.
>> 
>> Back to Top
>> 
>> **Changes to this Privacy Statement**
>> 
>> This document was last updated 29 June 2006. We will occasionally update this privacy statement. When we do, we will also revise the "last updated" date. 
>> 
>> Back to Top
>> 
>>  _Page updated: 29 June 2006_
